Michael Jerred

mjerred.com mjerred.work@gmail.com https://github.com/MikeJerred https://stackoverflow.com/users/4854046

Profile

I am an articulate and intelligent programmer, with a strong academic background and six years experience in the web development industry. I have had a real passion for programming since the age of 13, beginning by reverse engineering video games, and have taught myself multiple languages and technologies over the years.

I currently do contract work through my limited company: Linnet Digital Ltd.

Experience

Linnet Digital November 2016 - Current

XpKit Analytics Library

May 2018

2 week contract with Imagination

I built a javascript library to replicate the functionality of the segment io analytics library, but with some adjustments. I built it as an npm package using Typescript, complete with unit tests and generated documentation.

Wan Li Portfolio Site December 2017

1 week project

I built a portfolio site for UX designer Wan Li, using Angular to do some interesting animations.

Dragon CMS Project

January 2017 - July 2017

6 month contract with Centaur Media

I worked on building a large new CMS project built using Domain Driven Design. Event messages were sent from the browser to the server via WebSockets to make updates to the database, so that multiple users on the site would be able to see each others changes in real time. The front-end was built using Angular 4, and the back-end using C# Wep API. My specific role was to build parts of the front and back-end, advise on architectural decisions, and to build a tool to perform data migration.

LMI Reskin November 2016

1 month contract with Centaur Media

I worked with my previous full-time employer to help finish off one of the projects they had. This was a cosmetic redesign of The Lawyer Market Intelligence (see below), and was built in the same way using the same technologies.

Centaur Media

August 2014 - Feburary 2016

My role at Centaur was to write code for various ASP.NET projects, fixing bugs and developing new features on existing sites; as well as creating brand new sites, as part of a team of 6-7 developers. The sites were built using C# for the back-end, with Microsoft SQL Server for the database engine and Apache Solr for creating indexes. A combination of AngularJs, Bootstrap, Typescript, LESS, jQuery and Knockout were used for the front-end. Mercurial was used for version management.

One of my main achievements was to introduce the AngularJs framework to the team, and use this to create the front-end architecture for two major new projects. These were a great success and the company is now using Angular as a standard for future projects.

Example projects:

- The Lawyer Market Intelligence (thelawyermarketintelligence.com) I was the lead developer on this brand new site, which including building a custom CMS. I designed the architecture for the front-end with a combination of AngularJs, LESS and Typescript; and built a skeleton backend to interface with the database. After this initial phase the other developers joined in and we each worked on separate modules. Using this approach we were able to develop with a high degree of parallelization, and finished the project in a short space of time.
- Fashion Monitor (fashionmonitor.com) A new site was built for this product, but using an existing database. I used roughly the same architecture for the front-end as I used in the Lawyer Market Intelligence project, and we again developed it in a highly modular fashion with many developers working in parallel.
- Celebrity Intelligence (celebrityintelligence.com) My main involvement with this site was the creation of a search widget on the home page. It is able to filter by many different categories and display a count of the results very quickly, so to do this fast enough required using Apache Solr to create indexes from complex SQL queries.

Acturis August 2012 – June 2014

I worked as a junior developer using C#, Moq, SQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Technologies

Excellent C#, LINQ, ASP.NET, Node.js, Angular, Typescript, SASS/LESS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Competent ASP.NET Core, SQL, Apache Solr, Neo4j, Google Cloud Platform, x86 ASM, C++

Familiar Haskell, Tensorflow, MongoDB

Qualifications

2008 - 2012 MSci. Mathematics and Physics

University of Bristol

2008 UK Physics Olympiad

Gold medal & one of 15 chosen to attend the International Olympiad preparation camp University of Oxford

2006 - 2008 5x A2 Level, Physics Advanced Extension Award

Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths, Further Maths Additional *The Manchester Grammar School*

References available upon request.